♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 11=
I'm sorry.
If you didn't want to go with me,
you could have told me.
Why did you lie to me,
saying you wanted to elope with me?
Was I just a pawn
in your path of revenge,
merely to satisfy your selfish desires?
Miss Jiang said
that Rong Xiaonan treated her as a wife.
She also mentioned Rong Xiaonan's
selfish revenge or selfish desires.
What she said was "pawn".
A pawn.
That's right.
You can hate me.
No matter what, I'll clear your name.
That's what I owe you.
I don't need that.
If it weren't for you,
my father would still be alive,
and no one would be pointing fingers
at me, calling me a father-killer.
Rong Xiaonan,
wasn't I good to you?
Why did you harm me like this?
Miss Jiang,
I've never had the slightest intention
of causing you harm.
I bore the weight of the dozen lives
of the Rongqing Troupe.
I had no choice.
Rong Xiaonan has kept apologizing,
and Miss Jiang has kept being angry.
I'll keep eavesdropping for you.
Come back.
Who told you to eavesdrop?
I don't care at all what they say.
Now, do you think
your revenge has succeeded?
I'm telling you, Xu Fan is still alive.
He's safely recovering
at the Governor Mansion now.
The only one who died
in this farce is my father.
Your revenge is nothing but a joke.
(It's still warm. He was just here.)
The all-mighty, great governor
has fallen to such a state?
I beg you.
Letting you die now
would be letting you off too easy.
I should let you
be tormented day and night
by the wronged souls you killed.
Were you afraid I'd kill him,
so you waited here for me?
Looking at him now,
isn't he as good as the dead?
I promised to care for him
until his death.
Sparing his life now
will be my repayment for raising me.
You're benevolent to him, Governor Xu.
I didn't expect that you would
also keep your words at times.
After all, you still owe me
one unfulfilled promise.
I never owe anyone.
Governor,
the car to the Jiang residence is ready.
The top priority now
is to clear Miss Jiang's name.
Once I take back the Governor Mansion,
you're all dead.
Xu You'an took that opera singer
to the Jiang residence.
Jiang Chun'er is at the Governor Mansion.
We can't get to her.
If we can't do it openly, we go dark.
No matter what, Jiang Chun'er must die.
She mustn't become the chamber head.
It'd only secure the hold of Xu You'an.
Yes.
No cooperation, no way out.
Whether it's Jiang Chun'er or Xu You'an,
anyone who stands in my way
to the Buddha Head and the phoenix crown
must die.
I had people look into it.
No one went in or out
around the time it happened.
That means the murderer
must be very familiar with this place.
I'd like to see who
dares to play tricks in front of me.
The gun you stole
doesn't shoot straight.
Use this one.
Master,
please don't come back
as an evil ghost to kill us.
Yes,
every wrong has its owner.
Just go find the young lady.
We are all innocent.
What are you doing here so late?
We're afraid the master
will come back as an evil ghost.
Nonsense.
Since the master died,
rumors have been everywhere,
all saying the young lady murdered him.
Some even say...
Even say...
Say what?
They say she was possessed.
That's why she killed her own father.
They say the master will return
as an evil ghost to kill us all.
An evil ghost?
Killed her father?
Talk of ghosts and spirits
is all nonsense.
I will definitely catch the murderer
and make that "evil ghost"
vanish into ashes.
You're serving the Jiang family. Don't
gossip about Miss Jiang like others do.
Quickly put these things away.
- Yes.
Let's go.
I don't believe
we can't find a single clue.
You can eliminate one evil ghost,
but can you kill all the people
with evil in their hearts in this world?
(Song Mianxiang, police coroner)
After all, the victim's death
exactly matches the serial murder case
that shook Fengcheng eight years ago.
Nice to meet you.
Let me introduce myself.
I am...
Coming alone to the crime scene?
That's not normal.
I am the coroner with the police,
Song Mianxiang.
(Coroner's Certificate)
My certificate.
Does this count
as meeting the hard way, Governor?
(Song Mianxiang)
As a coroner,
why are you here late at night?
(Coroner's Certificate)
Who is this?
Just answer the question truthfully.
When I examined the victim's body,
I found his limbs were all broken,
and the way he died was odd.
So I came here to find the answers.
I checked Fengcheng's files. It matches
the cases from eight years ago.
It could be revenge or a copycat murder.
Why didn't you report your findings?
Why exactly did you come alone
to the crime scene at this hour?
Of course, to solve the case quickly,
earn your recognition,
and make sure you remember me.
Let's go to the police station.
Let's go.
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪